Connecticut Milk Producers Association Records
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Milk Producers Association Records.
1919-1947.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Connecticut Milk Producers Association.
85 linear feet.
MSS19790004
Based in Hartford, Connecticut, the Connecticut Milk Producers Association was a professional organization for the milk producers of Connecticut. It provided its members with a monthly newsletter and kept track of prices and production of milk within the state as well as in the neighboring states.
History
Based in Hartford, Connecticut, the Connecticut Milk Producers Association was a professional organization for the milk producers of Connecticut. It provided its members with a monthly newsletter and kept track of prices and production of milk within the state as well as in the neighboring states.
Scope and Content
The collection contains ledgers that document the quantity of milk purchased in Connecticut from 1922 through 1937. It appears that each member milk producer kept his own ledgers, which were then bound together by the CMPA with those of other members. The ledgers record patron names, amounts of milk specified and produced, and cost and payment for each milk producer. Each volume covers a six month period and is arranged alphabetically by name of milk producer. The Bulletin was issued monthly and is bound chronologically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Dairying--Economic aspects--Connecticut.; Dairying--Economic aspects--New England.; Milk trade--Connecticut.; Milk trade--New England.; Milk yield--Connecticut.; Milk yield--New England.
Document Types:
Publications.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The Record of Milk Purchased ledgers were acquired for the University of Connecticut by Professor E.A. Perregaux in the late 1940s or early 1950s. They were stored in the Wilbur Cross Library until 1979, when they were transferred to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University Libraries.
Acquisition Information
The Bulletins were originally sent from the Connecticut Milk Producers Association to the Economic Service of Connecticut State College (now University of Connecticut). The Library collected the Bulletins and bound them into five volumes. They were moved to the Archives in 1993 to become part of the CMPA collection. The correspondence and records of the association auditor and accountant, Irving Goldblatt, were donated in April 2011 by his family.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Record of Milk Purchased Ledgers, 1922-1937
  - 1922 April - 1923 March (Box 1)
  - 1923 April - 1923 September (Box 2)
  - 1923 October - 1924 March (Box 3)
  - 1924 April - 1924 September (Box 4)
  - 1924 October - 1925 March (Box 5)
  - 1925 April - 1925 September (Box 6)
  - 1925 October - 1926 March (Box 7)
  - 1926 April - 1926 September (Box 8)
  - 1926 October - 1927 March (Box 9)
  - 1927 April - 1927 September (Box 10)
  - 1927 October - 1928 March (Box 11)
  - 1928 April - 1928 September (Box 12)
  - 1928 October - 1929 March (Box 13)
  - 1929 April - 1929 September (Box 14)
  - 1929 October - 1930 March (Box 15)
  - 1930 April - 1930 September (Box 16)
  - 1930 October - 1931 March (Box 17)
  - 1931 April - 1931 September (Box 18)
  - 1931 October - 1932 March (Box 19)
  - 1932 April - 1932 September (Box 20)
  - 1932 October - 1933 March (Box 21)
  - 1933 April - 1933 September (Box 22)
  - 1933 October - 1934 March (bound) (Box 23)
  - 1934 April - 1934 September (Box 24)
  - 1934 October - 1935 March (Box 25)
  - 1935 April - 1935 September (bound) (Box 26)
  - 1935 October - 1936 March (Box 27)
  - 1936 October - 1937 March (bound) (Box 28)
- Series II: Bulletins, 1919-1947
  - v. I Nos. 1 - 72, 1919 August - 1925 July (Box 29)
  - v. II Nos. 73 - 173, 1925 August - 1933 December
  - v. III Nos. 174 - 256, 1934 January - 1940 December
  - v. IV Nos. 257 - 304, 1941 January - 1944 December
  - v. V Nos. 305 - 340, 1945 January - 1947 December
- Series III: Correspondence and financial records, 1935-1936
  - Correspondence and financial records of of Irving Goldblatt, auditor/accountant for the association, 1935-1936 (Box 30)